I have this memory of a time in my life
when I knew that I was unhappy and I
knew I wanted to make a change, but I
was so afraid that maybe what I have is
actually great, but I just don't have
the perspective to see it. Like maybe
I'm being ungrateful. Maybe if I make
the change and I leave where I am, I'll
look back and be like, "Oh it was
so great and I didn't know and now it's
too late to go back." And my friend says
to me, Tessa,
knowing this is not enough is enough of
a reason to make a change. We can never
know if the next thing will be better or
worse. All we know right now is knowing
this is not enough is enough. And when
she said this to me, I had a visual in
my head, a feeling that I was on a train
barreling in a direction. And she was
suggesting to me that I jump out of a
moving vehicle into the darkness, like
rolling down a hill. And I'm like, okay,
well, that's scary. And if I get out,
the train is going to keep going without
me. But I had this clarity that where
the train is going is not a destination
I want to be at. So,
I'm not saying I'm right. I am just
saying that this is what I believe.
Knowing this is not enough is enough.
And here's a little song about that.
[music]
>> [music]
>> I have this image in my head. [music]
I am on a train going somewhere I don't
want to go. [music] To my left [singing]
is the open air fighting me to jump out
[music] on the hill.
But that'd be insane. [music] It's so
much easier to be here on this train
[singing] going somewhere I don't want
to go. [music] And besides, what if I
get off? Find I like the new place even
less.
[music]
Knowing
this is not enough is [singing] enough.
Knowing [singing]
this is not enough is enough. [music]
I don't like the way it feels being here
with you. [music] I can never tell
[singing] what's real and what is true.
But somewhere inside my body, I am
saying I don't want this anymore.
[music]
Once I've heard it, then I've heard
[singing] it. You can't [music] stop me
now. I will honor and protect her. I
will not allow myself to [music]
squander [singing] one more day.
Accepting lessons she deserves. [music]
Knowing
[music] this is not enough is enough.
[singing]
knowing
this is not enough [singing] is enough
[music]
my friend. [singing]
She says
[music] what stranges
nothing [singing]
changes [music] if nothing
changes. [singing]
[music]
Oh, [singing]
give yourself the grace to start again.
If it hurts you, put it down. [music] If
it don't serve [singing] you, look
around. You're doing great, my babe. I
swear you're going to make it. [music]
You never can know what could come. And
it's not done until it's done. You're
doing great, [singing] my babe. I swear
you're going to make it. I can [music]
do hard things [singing]
parallel
parking
[music] like it all. It just [singing]
takes practicing. [music]
I [singing] can walk a new path. I can
get [singing and music]
myself back. I can learn
[singing and music] to be a better
friend.
Give myself [music] the grace to try
again.
[music]
>> [music]
>> All right, that's my song. What do I
want to tell you? That song's called
Knowing This Is Not Enough is Enough or
something different if I change my mind
by the time this comes out. And it's out
now everywhere you find music. Uh my
name is Tessa Violet and I'm putting out
a new song every month this year off my
new album called There Will Be Joy. And
if you want to be notified when the next
one comes out, there'll be a link in the
description. Um, also, if you really
want to be a friend, uh, I have a
Patreon and this year I'm doing a
postcard for every song I put out. I'll
print a little lyrics on the back and
then autograph them. Um, what else do I
want to tell you? Listen, if you're
afraid to make a change, all paths lead
to the same destination. And you get to
pick what you do with your life. And
maybe there is no wrong choice. That's
what I believe. All right. Sending love.